[Music]
the Masonic can be plural it doesn't
have to be on throat area that's a
terrible mistake to think it is and the
only reason it's been authoritarian is
because ever since ancient Egypt we had
the boy Pharaohs of Egypt the 11 year
olds the sudden were the tyrants of
Egypt and decided absolutely everything
and started by killing all the priests
so they get rid of any opposition to
their own truths ok these guys built the
pyramids the most useless things that
were built in human history these guys
also created the moon landing in 1969
which was absolutely useless so when the
boys string bobbing gods we have the
problems with the phallus that go wrong
mmm and we also should watch out before
we look for a fire to watch out for the
fake phalluses and they're always the
ones that are cheap go straight to the
heart to us and appeal to our dirtiest
shadows inside of us and they do so by
uniting us around something we can hate
oh yeah the scapegoat again or the
object
ranae's yards writes extensively about
this you look Restivo right successfully
about this one of the great achievements
of European 20th century philosophy was
the understanding of scapegoating and
how fundamental it is to human identity
but so let's let's pause there because
that's very very important right so yes
phallus you're talking about okay is the
danger of it is when it becomes a
mechanism for scapegoating you know yes
and and that and that's the danger so
that's what we have to avoid and that's
how we can understand what a healthy
fellows exactly she would be yeah
exactly
and this is where we're not really sure
art comes into the picture who was a
French philosophers very influential in
America and I think because here art
said that scapegoating is the only way
we can unify that's how we always unify
people then of course then you assume
that all utopian visions are bad and
dangerous and must be avoided but that
is just an intellectual disqualification
that's not sorry not permitted you know
you got to go back and retry everything
even if you fail the
sometimes before because you got to look
at every option you got to turn every
stone you otherwise you're not a
philosopher so you go back and study it
and see what did go wrong and why and
then you discover that we also have
beautiful phallic missions that are
actually have been accomplished in
history because they have been
accomplished that were successful
phallus is concerned exist and they can
save humanity if you like and so for
example declaration so roster did this
or asterism three thousand seven years
ago kick-started a religion that we can
use today three thousand seven hundred
years later and say that wait a second
it is genuinely the phallic visions that
have changed humanity for the better
throughout history and every time we got
stuck and needed saving it was final
equations that did that mm-hmm
so give me some examples of historical
examples okay you can understand first
of all but this is from the perspective
of the people who leave one territory to
go into the next one
mm-hmm I mean hey when the Hebrews
arrived in the promised land they
committed genocide so you gotta
understand that it's depending on the
circumstances what was available to you
it might not necessarily look good for
everybody in Universal Manor
of course we hope that with the machines
we can do it more smoothly and you know
less bloody but you know at the end of
the day say for example Columbus
conquering America put Europe into a
golden age then somebody produce a well
look at the Native Americans and how
badly they were traded and they got sick
from smallpox and everything
what that's absolutely true but from the
perspective of European culture you
cannot deny the fact that you're a
prospered conquered three continents and
became the wealthiest part of the planet
and eventually the really messianic part
of that was of course in the 19th
century when building the ride is an
ideal in Germany and Scandinavia and
people realized that if everybody can
read and write and count in a society if
everybody gets schooling we'll all be
better off that is the genuine messianic
the Messianic is the trick with the
Messianic is that if somebody finds out
a game that everybody benefits from
and where the overall cost benefit
analysis is just enormous benefit
compared to the cost involved so that's
often when the Messianic appears but I
want to go I want to go a little bit
back because your examples again they
were there's always a scapegoat involved
all right there was I just finished
reading George book sorry yeah so you
know when Columbus went to America the
scapegoat might be the the Savage or you
know or when you know the Jews went went
no no no no no there was no there was no
scapegoat involved I mean people in
America were treated horribly no doubt
about that but there wasn't scapegoating
involved Columbus did not go back to
your percent I need to raise bigger
funds so that we can kill the awful
savages of America no he went back and
said I plundered them I've taken their
gold away from them and I can get you
more gold if you give you more money two
more boats okay fair enough
that's not the same thing as
scapegoating that difference is very
very important to make that distinction
so at the end of the day of its often
after military victories say Napoleon
yeah you wander Europe you know but even
in 1807 at the forward of her monologist
spirit legal rights to the German people
I know that Napoleon plundered us last
year I know he raped all our daughters
killed all our sons literally just that
yeah and then Olin was typically it was
the apocalypse it was typical German
he's totally torn apart I don't care
right say go Napoleon is the zeitgeist
he is the shit he is the time spirit he
is the new thing all we Germans need to
do is to imitate him and construct if
different kinds of institutions based on
apollyon system and that is the birth of
the modern nation-state if you don't
understand war and if you don't
understand conquest and if you don't
understand that war can benefit you when
you go to war you don't understand
hunting
that's exactly we stuck with social
justice warriors or regressive vegans
and go after people because of the
tonality their etiquette the fucked up
situation were currently in especially
North America and increasingly Europe
because we don't understand phallic
energy and he lost respect for it and we
think we have to get away from it and
medicate ourselves out of it and that is
terrible that would be the ultimate
disaster because it was precisely the
kind of environment in Germany in the
1920s okay none of these guys we talk
about here a part of anglo-saxon
spiritual discourse at the moment ever
go to martial arts scholars they dislike
they refuse to understand masculine
sexual energy mm-hmm okay
if you try to avoid that and that's half
humanity how the fuck are gonna take
people out of an existential crisis like
I said this is all like people sitting
in Egypt refusing to move not listening
to mosun era cause they're dangerous
because they're utopian right okay well
the noses are did golf tour of the
country and create genocide that's true
but at least it got you out of slavery
so you stuck in Egypt and you're having
your little coffee you skip the coffee
you talk about tonality that's again and
you didn't even see that you're chained
so what should we do then
where's it going what I'm working on the
grand narrative you know I think any
decent philosopher today has to do that
and the two ways of doing it you either
go down into deep history with John for
Varkey and Jordan Pederson and coming
Tagle do brilliantly okay I also go into
deep history I possibly go deeper than
they do I go into what she dealers
called an Amidala G no Maggie so so
understanding what humans have to be on
the move also understanding why time is
essential rather than space also just
down by process central rather than
object variety agrees with me on all
these things the great thing of beauty
Simmons arrestin ism is to both modest
and the both process-oriented so the two
religions have a lot in common
they just two different narratives and
and the Buddhist one whichever arc is
that I need to get everybody with me I
need to put everybody push everybody
forward I need to make people survive
because otherwise they fall into the
chaos that is Jon Jordan Peterson this
is Jon for Warka this is what they work
with but where are people going to go he
does they don't respond to that question
it's like they still sitting there
completely obsessed with the etiquette
of the dinner party
and no dinner is served there's no
content okay so long titties phallic so
so where's the next question is where's
the promised land well it's certainly
not on the moon yeah murmurs the
promised land the name of the promised
land is sago topia the name of the
promised land is the cost Nepal so the
cost Nepal the idea that all the world
becomes one city mm-hmm
the idea of akuto pia is that the entire
planet is cultivated and we have sensors
everywhere to measure climate and
weather and everything so we know what
we're doing and we create a sustainable
system where we employed resources
rather than exploit resources which is
the fermentation that sustainable system
on this planet is secreto Pia the hubris
today is to think we're gonna leave the
planet that's nonsense
we're not gonna leave the planet we
can't even live outside of this planet
as humans so we're gonna stay on this
planet for the foreseeable future for
thousands of years to come
and we're gonna make sure this planet
even if I will climate change that the
costs are taken care of for climate
change and that we can still survive on
this planet as human beings and we're
gonna survive as human beings on this
planet in collaboration with machines
and if these machines only sedate us
give us entertainment and keep us you
know in more teto
like you know living dead which is where
the courage is what the Internet
currently does then were there were real
deep trouble but if the machines can
collaborate with us to make us more
creative and more experimental that's
wonderful here is where I agree with
market completely except that he doesn't
set out a goal we were gonna go he
doesn't even give it a name and my name
for that it costs for polygenism and Eko
tokenism and we're working on a third
ISM and that's gonna be the next book
we're working on we set this out of the
synthesis buck and I don't know so you
don't know why don't we throw that
question why do we throw that Western
forward to the people who follow us
actually this is really wonderful loyal
followers we have a follow us at these
discussions
yes there has to be it's going to be
third one I
sort of sense where we're heading with
the third one but a koto P is the name
of the planet where will a sustainable
yeah okay cut the Cosmo Paul II kind of
life are gonna live meaning that to get
out of the nation-state and to create an
truly global Empire that actually works
the Consul call this the idea we're
gonna go forward okay and here many of
the very philosophers the poggle and
Peterson go after like Dara da for
example have done wonderful work if you
just bothered to study Derrida and start
11 else and study some okra tree and
study the other writers out every
actually work with the idea across on
positivism a lot of work has been done
across proposes we're trying to sense it
that we can tap into I like that yeah
yeah I mean I think that's I think
that's unarguable like okay I could
Tokyo cosmopolitan for me that's been
arguable not going to need and that's
where we're going I mean that's what
we're trying to do already
obstacles to doing that but it's not
going to emerge by some spiritual ladies
having coffee sitting babbling together
listening to Charlie authentically
relating we're not gonna happen there at
all it's gonna happen because some
people make an effort and study
engineering for years you know and going
to the tiny minute details of physics
and biology and anything you need to
work with understand and develop whole
new materials and invent new things this
is why I'm an epitope Ian I'm Pro
nuclear power because we need huge
amounts of cheap abundant electricity
for all this to work we cannot save the
planet unless we're cheap abundant
electricity everywhere and sensors
everywhere we can't do that I'm also for
genetically modifying things I think
genetical modification is the beauty of
Agriculture and and the beauty of what
human beings have done the past 5,000
years by creating civilization again I
saw a state idea we can build on the
previous generations understanding of
the world we don't have to make the
mistakes and we can then improve them
things and this constant improvement we
can do because of it civilization ISM is
real it's absolutely real but we now
need it one step further to nurture 10
billion people on this planet for the
for SIBO
future mi response that is a katoki
anism and cosmopolitanism but this can
be more to it because we also have to go
deep into religion that's the third one
and the most important thing the most
important thing there is to understand
the difference between public teaching
and mysticism so what can be said in
public and what cannot be said in public
hmm because what what you can't say in
pop you can't say something in public
that people are bound to misunderstand
yeah academia is all about publishing
everything in public that's more words
yes exactly you got it so in new
exoteric in the new esoteric have to be
defined and this is problematic because
you're used to the fact that if you
close the door to room and some people
sit inside the room and they're powerful
then they create a little power click
and you want to send journalists and you
want to send reporters in there and
discover what they're doing and expose
it and all those things and because we
live in the first stage of digital which
is all about transparency or rather
because everything will be memorized you
might as well go public with it from day
one now we need a dialectical reaction
against that although it's very very
hard
and the question is this if you go into
room with some people that you deeply
trust how the fuck do you keep the
smartphone's out of there you know
hmm that is key here itself to
strip-search somebody at the door every
time and even then they probably implant
something in the future or I would say
this where could you train the capacity
to be mystical and esoteric and keep
knowledge to yourself because of a
misunderstood if it goes public
well former can I share an interest I
think Peter said those two is called
psychedelics okay psychedelics this is
far as I know illegal in all Western
countries yeah he generally legal uh
what's good about getting involved with
something that he's illegal personally I
I only take drugs in Peru or something
uh what you trained yourself in being a
satiric you can't talk about it in
public because if you talk about it in
public then the police needs to rest you
said you did you know you just locked up
so you trained yourself and keep it
quiet about something other people who
train with this are for example people
who work within the opposition in China
and Iran China and Iran are currently
dictatorships one of them is Shia Muslim
leadership the other one is a communist
dictatorship
these two dictatorships China and Iran
if you live within those cultures you're
trained in being esoteric all the time
there's tons and things you must not
talk about or you can talk about them in
an encrypted fashion mm-hmm then you get
close to the hackers the most
interesting people out there at the
moment the hackers are they are the army
of the next Moses in error mmm okay so
when hackers start a go spiritual not
not and the sexy middle-class people
remember with the hackers started no
spiritual really interesting shit is
going to happen then you get into the
mysticism that we need today and well I
didn't write about this at all in the
synthesis of book because the mysticism
it was sort of it's sort of in between
the lines right but I think that's an
ideal the idea we need to explore
because what is lacking next echo
tokenism and cosmopolitanism it's a sort
of deep religion understanding of deep
religion mhm mhm and and and this is
really you're being told this because we
trust you will you being told this
because you're also part of developing
it further mm-hmm okay but you cannot go
public with this because if you go
public with this it will be
misunderstood and all hell will break
loose yeah well yeah and I'm involved in
certain things like this at which I
absolutely certain could not be public
right yeah yeah I'm sure you are too but
but but it just could not be public just
William I would not be the least bit
understood so instead of looking for
these people who pride themselves to
being transparent everybody
telling everybody to everything they go
through their lives look for people
actually are trained to keep quiet about
things of course I'm a psychoanalyst I
must keep quiet about what my analyst
songs tell me mm-hmm
according to law I must even keep quiet
about them trying to commit suicide
the only profession well you're not even
allowed to call the police if somebody's
gonna commit suicide it's the cyclist
of course you're trained in keeping
quiet about things if you work within
the company that works at patents and
most companies do today so this is a
trade secret you better keep quiet about
it so but this is getting increasingly
hard in a society of the pressure is
being pushed if everything was
transparent and we knew everything about
everybody then the world would be better
off and all I same people say that is
that you don't really want a camera
inside your wife's pussy do you when you
fuck her right okay unless you're a porn
star but you know it's privacy is also
an understanding or something you don't
go public with you know so privacy will
return in the big way mm-hmm yeah we
call it employ tation privacy and and
the right to intimacy of some kind but
the problem here is that it's a class
issue so the people who will go private
about their lives are the ones who can
afford to be private mmm
gated communities yeah what is a gated
community it is it is a wall we put up
around a place that people live and
you're not allowed to look in unless a
liver mm-hmm so but I still can you can
have gated communities that are not
based on class you can have you know you
can have schools of practice and things
like that
esoteric practices that are not based on
class well you do create class because
you have external and internal okay the
second you turn somebody down who knocks
the door and says no you're not allowed
in we can't have you here mm-hmm
naivety has to go but it's not because
of their their their socioeconomic
status it's because they're they're not
prepared to do or to play the game
that's being played at that but listen
weak Alyssa we killed capitalism in our
first book called the netic rats and we
replaced it with something called
potential ism class today is at Angeles
it's not capitalist you can't say
socio-economic any longer you have to
say cultural class you culture class
defines socioeconomic class so the
culture class you belong to determines
what kind of socio-economic class you're
gonna you're going to belong to further
down the ladder the attentional
society's already arrived we are living
in a world we'll be looking for nodes in
a chaos those nodes are called
algorithms
you know sometimes they're also people
that lead us and we look for anybody can
lead us out of the chaos were it and
that's we do with algorithms every
morning we go online and want to make
informed decisions about the things we
do in our lives and because we go
through that filter before we decide
anything else
capitalism is dead and over and we've
already moved into the age of
attentional ISM mm-hmm and everything
now it's about the science of attention
mmm where do people go how long do they
stay do they return to the recommended
do the use the different services
offered are the interacting with and
identifying with their actions mm-hmm
the whole science of attention is
booming today because it is of course
the only way to get through to people so
potential ISM is already a fact okay so
that's how we have to understand class
today and that means class today is all
about teaching human beings social
intelligence teach them engineering
teaching them art languages psychology
anything that improves your chances of
collaborating with and communicating
with other people so you're talking
about a kind of new pragmatic form of
Education which is just sitting in a
classroom and listening to a professor
speak you're actually learning what you
need to learn Zachary Stein yes that's
funny because I was just thinking about
my own experience as you know I teach in
the University and there's that that
part of my life which is so separate
from the part of my life was just
talking to you and being connected to
all these people or I'm almost like it's
almost like to two different worlds you
know what I mean you're living Simon
in this old world which is dying you
know it's like uh and then and then and
then there's this whole kind of other
thing being born or being been created
yeah so I guess it's new it's not
self-organizing I liked what you said
before so be a vision but it's
self-organizing with a vision yeah it's
a bit it's a bit like the current
discourse spiritual discourse is a bit
like okay we got a problem with
schooling here we don't know what
schools are gonna do in the future so
we've got to put all the students
together in the ring and they're gonna
talk and authentically relate to each
other and they will suddenly solve
everything because the solution to the
problem of the schools of the future
will suddenly emerge out of that
conversation mm-hmm you'd hear how
ridiculous that sounds
how the heck would students know so you
have to make new institutions and well
you gotta wait until somebody comes
along and has some messianic vision for
how we can distribute social
intelligence to more people and for
those who aren't born with it trained
those who need training they can be
socially intelligent and behave in
increasingly social world so that's why
it's interesting like that's like the
what the philosopher is in a way he's
kind of a messiah comes with like
there's not been that many great
philosophers in the world right there's
only a few right and they always change
that world in this radical sense and
they're kind of like the Messiah that
you're talking priests see when they do
one person who is who just changes the
entire world like dick hard or the next
or Hegel or so there'd the priestly
version of the Messianic okay okay what
I'm talking about here is the chief 10
verse on the mass addict who goes at the
front not Arab I'm talking about Moses
mm-hmm so that's the difference so Moses
is where we need to tie into the
machines and certainly the machines will
help soothe a priestly messianic mission
too
because priests certainly don't have
problem hiring machines to do things for
them and and um so who's Moses he's not
an intellectual particularly he's like
who's my briefs I am after researching
this with young very clever engineers of
Scandinavia at the moment and what we're
doing is a basically putting forward a
drawing board
and they were saying how about the
engineers chieftain how about the
engineers priest and we discovered that
some of the guys to study the
engineering and are very successful at
it now and they're in their early
thirties are discovering I have more the
priest the archetype person another guy
in the room goes yeah but I have more
the chief tamely you know I teach
engineers and managers you know so the
engineers are more likely in the
priestly caste and the managers are more
like the I'm teaching nothing but
digital transformation leadership from
next year you know that's all I'm
teaching that was kind of it so and and
this is very interesting because then we
get an idea of engineering yeah that
goes into GPS or what is engineering
where did you start from and you know
that's good question yeah and the
disasters in history like the Tower of
Babel could the Tower of Babel be built
today and no longer be disaster that's a
question that's interesting to ask why
did we go to the moon who came up with
that idea you know it you know these
feats for good or bad need to be
redefined and revisited and that's what
young engineers are incredibly
interested in and once you've got a
bunch of engineer standing at the top of
their toes in the room you certainly
talking about the phallic and then you
and are working in a territory where
currently the spiritual discourse or
North America isn't even close to so II
I find it complimentary the kind of work
with you I think both projects need to
be respected I think there's a
tremendous value out of a dialog coming
out of this I hope to have it the
Ferranti for example I think this
tremendous about dialogue coming out of
this and if you're and pedis understands
it comes out of it so roster next to me
that even better because you know we're
talking about is the ID or the jordan
penis and the so Rastan and John from
arc of the Buddhist in a dialogue with
each other so it's a sore ass some of
the buddhist goes in dollar with each
other if the phallic and the magical
going to dialogue with each other we can
both talk about the new grand narrative
that's needed and we could also talk
about the
Tayna within which that narrative must
arrive okay that's that's nice that's a
nice picture
oh very Aristotelian but question for
you yeah I got a question for you and
often you're talking about the phallus
and young men being young women these
days they have to do know young women
young women will certainly feel a lot of
attraction to this whole sort of Western
Buddhist approach spirituality
complexity is something they understand
by nature that's a bunny to Royce a
woman okay
many the many women in the field of
complexity science and they do great
work no I don't think that it's a
problem women at all and also women are
way more socially intelligent than men
are by nature so the average young woman
today has four times as many Facebook
friends as the average young man so I
don't worry about that which others take
care of so ironically Jordan Peterson
has put the foot on something which he
hasn't fulfilled which is the need for
final ignition because that was
explosive behind Jordan Peters and all
these other voices have stepped forward
but they're all talking about the
magical here or feminine they're talking
about the container and little that's a
way that's the self-organizing thing
that works by itself whereas the male is
something that needs to be developed
that's why there's men's groups and
that's why that's why so many cultures
circumcise their boys is it's like
reminding the boys every time you look
down your foreskins gone you're reminded
that this first kid was taken away from
you you're a kid because in your own
nature as you are you're dangerous but
when you're cultured and trained and
domesticated you'll be wonderful it is
the understanding that the shift from
nature of the culture the containment of
sexuality the control of sexuality so
that is directed in the right direction
makes all the difference this is what
growing up is all about this is why we
have the three stages of the child of
the adult and of the God so if the child
aspires to be the God all hell breaks
loose if the child
to imitate to one day become a grown-up
go through proper rite of passage the
learns is still young or she's still
young need to learn more but you know
respected as a grown-up because you can
support yourself then you come into the
mode where you can even be a parent you
can contribute to the larger community
you create value that's way more than
you need for yourself you create an
abundance of value of some kind then you
really truly a grown-up then you shine
and you have the years where you shine
and then eventually you become an older
person who needs the support of others
again materially but you supply the
wisdom this whole chain is with no
madala ji is over the lifespan so this
numerology over the lifespan is the
filter through which we need to
understand what it means to be boy a man
and a god or a girl a woman or a goddess
and the God and the goddess are only
transcendental ideals that we have to
know where we're gonna go next when were
grown up so what do you aspire to as a
grown-up you aspire to create something
bigger and better than yourself for your
children to inherit this is fundamental
to civilization mm-hmm and creating this
heritage but others can build them to
create something even better and even
more beautiful it's just the next step
on the Tower of Babel that you're
building this is what civilization this
is fundamentally Zoroastrian it was a
sore ass Jones who discovered this some
little more than 3,000 years ago started
seeing the beauty and civilization and
realize that when we settle down we take
the nomadic energy and instead of
spending it on traveling through a
physical landscape we instead travel
through our ideas we started to do 5000
years ago was that okay we still on the
move but we're now on the move through
ideas and technology rather we're on the
move literally through landscape and
that's when we stopped being nomadic we
settle down and we could create
civilization but we still have to
understand ourselves as no matter
logical and this is where I take social
philosophy into the realm of process
philosophy the other end will process
philosophy is exploding at the moment is
of physics and that's because physics is
now moving into loop quantum gravity
it's moving into the holographic
principle and if you study physics in
the holographic principle
discover that's just process philosophy
taken to extreme in the physical
environment I'm doing the same thing
with the social environment I'm taking
process philosophy into social and what
I'm discovering and then is that if you
understand social completely and how
human beings relate to each other we
need to go back to the original nomadic
tribe this saucy on the sauce hunt or
sociology is the study of what the
original tribe might have looked like
yeah the tribe that we lived in for the
longest possible times it shaped our
genetic makeup more than anything else
yeah so that's it so it's all it's like
the arrow goes to both ways it goes
forward the future vision is by going as
far back as possible you know yeah but a
lot of guys these days start with
talking about the Big Bang and they make
a powerful presentation about the Big
Bang that didn't even happen by the way
but you know that's not interesting to
us as human beings
but the interest as human beings is the
beginning of life yeah whenever that
happened first on this planet and the
story of the origin of life is a human
on this planet stay on this planet and
try to create it and that's where the
origin of life is the story that needs
to be retold and deepened to then
understand echo topia whereas the story
of the cosmic pole is the store of human
beings settle down and start to go
nomadic in their minds yeah and their
ideas traveled and their ideas were on
the move and that movement will be
accomplished with establishments of the
cost of all these two major products in
turn when you internalize them then
becomes the difference between esoteric
and exoteric and where you put what do I
keep my mouth shut about what do I tell
people in public becomes a value you
have to make depending on the overall
goal now you started thinking utopianism
probably they didn't so unless
guys out there don't evolve sexuality
what they say they're faking it
okay don't trust anybody doesn't have a
functioning sex life to begin with you
can't do philosophy without sexuality
you can't you got to get your own dick
you don't pussy into it you know it's
just you can't do art without it just
banal so what do you think philosophy
will be anything but by now if people
pretended this was some kind of dialogue
we have in salons with our clothes on
and sexuality doesn't exist
it becomes infant talk because of it
unless there's a deep understanding and
a deep involvement that sexuality into
the world of philosophy it's not
philosophy proper then you haven't
really understood what Nietzsche meant
will will to power and will we setec
listen I call will to intelligence the
other day understood will unless you
first understand horny
you don't stand horny unless you
understand sexuality so exactly so the
anglo-saxon you know Daniel sucks and
Tara fication chemical to that are you
terrified of something the tariff
occation looking forward is like a
culture that immerse itself in a terror
of something so the tariff occasional
sexuality that is so predominant in
anglo-saxon culture you know it's just
it just comes back and bites you in the
ass because if you try to do philosophy
or even metaphysics without sexuality
you're just a little boy or a little
girl dreaming you're not doing the
proper job yet
the Freudian revolution means that we
can do philosophy without sexuality as
longer at least accordingly and and the
tantric of course always knew this right
sexuality was always in philosophy if
you were an Easter so that's in India
Iran China let's take it for granted I
don't know where this prudishness came
from in Europe probably from
Christianity but it didn't help us much
and and all I say to people is that
never trust a guy who doesn't have a
functioning sex life right cuz that
would permeates into everything he says
and thinks what I don't trust a monk or
something leader o monks often have very
functioning
because their tantric yeah no no I would
say people who thought seriously about
it and made decisions on how they're
gonna direct their sexual energy into
something more spiritual they know what
they're talking about
I don't people who are unable to embody
that well people who tried to avoid it
right are going to just abstraction and
intellectualization in the mind because
they they're just uncomfortable in a
body and exactly so I don't trust
anybody speaks highly of young but
refuses to deal with Freud was young
tries to desexualize Freud's work he
goes off in some really interesting
directions because of it
he's very useful but at the end of the
day there's a sexuality lacking in Jung
he probably fucked his patients that's
what he did okay
he was quite sexual yeah but you eat in
terms of activity but you know the
problem was that his work then wasn't
consequent with that so ya know Yuki was
not a I've heard he was not a father
figure like he was more like everybody's
friend aim is cool but you can't do
young without Friday or you missed the
point entirely
and with Hegel it's the opposite way
Hegel has enormous phallic energy but
the phallic energy in Hegel is
completely turned into theoretical game
what it's like it's like a priest to
Dawson of a chieftain and place the
priest a game fully that's why I'm a
higer Leo you can't be a priest up being
a galleon yeah because he go makes you
think
okay so you learn how to think from
Hegel but the consequence of Hegel what
he left behind was precisely the
revolution of the 19th century when
Schopenhauer
Darvin Freud and Nietzsche came along
and they all dealt with willpower the
old that willpower was what puts things
on the move what do you yeah energy yes
the will is your like energy this will
the children our
exactly it is magical energy to be
honest about Betty's definitely phallic
energy because it is a world towards
something whereas magical energy is
willed to contain something so the
that's exactly why that happened in
Europe in the 19th century that's
exactly why the French and the Germans
still go nude bathing and I'm kinky
clubs and everything and you know they
let their children swim around naked
whereas America you put a bikini on the
kid when the kid turns 2 so the
prudishness of anglo-saxon culture is
problematic and it's especially
problematic when you're gonna deal with
something called philosophy and AD
philosophy to the mix of politics and
spirituality so you're gonna end up with
something that lacks sexuality and lacks
sex so because it lacks sex don't trust
it um that's what you and I are going to
Tantra to understand Tantra because you
know these are traditions that are
thousands of years old that unify our
thinking our mind with sexuality so you
become a fully embodied person so that I
think is key here very important as we
go forward I hope for more dialogue I
hope for more work I'm sure there are
other guys out there who see things the
way we do and I've discovered the same
things we've discovered we'll have to go
into Dharma with you and I love the
intellectual deep web it's a storm a
little forum online but it's a good
place to go not dark web deep web mm-hmm
connect to deep ways a good place to go
to find out the people who are thinking
about these things in a very sort of
straightforward and open manner and um
good dialogue by the way speaking of
ladies sitting together the group to see
what emerges but you know but at the end
of the day I don't think the Messianic
has got to come out of these
conversations mmm it's not
we will probably provide some tips for
people who design technological
intelligence if they care to lism but at
the end of the day the Messianic is
going to come out of a few people who
really in a concentrated way has sat
down and thought through this properly
at a distance and it can then step back
as Seamus from the forest put on the
priestly robe and coming to the arena
tell us what they see it's not gonna
merge out a little ladies having coffee
and babbling forever
no it's gonna merge other people who've
done deep deep studies yeah when he's do
deep history deep psychology deep
science and we need to go deep we need
to understand physics we need to
understand biology and you can't do
complexity theory and you say will
something just emerge and he was you
know bigger than the sum of its parts
but that's just sloppy what is emergence
yeah well in sneaker and other guys have
worked extensively on this they should
try to solve this in what is an
emergence and what qualitative
differences are there between emergences
there's certainly hierarchy of
emergences just humans not all events
are equal some events are way more
valuable to us than other than sorry and
this study is called of ontology it's
also new area philosophy today we need
an ontology we need to understand what
is it along the time axis the realest
value to us which ones are the
singularities which ones are the
emergence which one are the events that
happen among the time axis why are they
valuable to us and how do we relate that
to our own spiritual experiences so we
can contain and cultivate those
experiences and memorize them and use
them so all of this work has to be done
yeah in ontology know it all oh gee are
my two favorite areas at the moment that
I work with they tie into many of the
traditional areas like better physics
and phenomenology but that's where I
work at the moment and anybody's
interested in these things and he's
working on it or a student of these
matters please get in contact with us
and we'll start the dialogue and we'll
go forward together okay you just said
50 about 50 things that could could be
other conversations yeah I don't really
know where to go now well I got the
silver found us this time